Welcome to the demonstration
video for cleaning the
horizontal Laminar airflow
workbench.
You will find the step by step
procedural lab in the textbook.
The compounder has performed
hand hygiene and garbing
procedures.
All the supply items to clean
the laminar airflow workbench
have been wiped down with
sterile isopropyl alcohol.
Hand sanitize the gloves with
the sterile IPA.
Open the outer packaging of the
sterile low lint wipers in the
outer 6 inches of the primary
engineering control.
You'll bring 6 wipers onto the
DCA.
You'll throw away that outer
packaging in the waste
container.
You'll hand sanitize your hands
with sterile IPA and allowed to
dry.
You can separate the wipers
before adding the cleaning
products to follow your
facilities.
SOP's many facilities will
incorporate using sterile water
for injection or sterile water
for irrigation as a primary
cleaning agent to remove residue
on all the surfaces of the hood.
The order of cleaning will be
the grill, the ceiling, the hang
bar and hooks, side panel, side
panel and work surface.
Open the EPA approved sterile
one step disinfectant saturate
the wipers don't over saturate.
We don't want it to pull on the
DCA.
Keep the cap in the air flow
recap.
Bring the bottle out of the
hood, Sanitize the gloves with
sterile IPA and we'll pick up a
wipe and we'll clean the screen
of the HEPA filter.
Be careful to not allow liquid
to enter the small holes and
cause damage to the HEPA filter.
We're doing overlapping side to
side strokes from the top of the
screen to the bottom.
Then you'll place the wiper in
the waste container and you'll
hand sanitize with sterile IPA.
We'll take a second wiper and
we'll clean the ceiling of the
PEC overlapping side to side
strokes.
Starting from the back corner of
the primary engineering control
till you reach the outside edge.
You can finish off cleaning that
outer edge of the ceiling you're
going to hand sanitize with
sterile IPA.
You'll pick up a third wiper and
you'll clean the hang bar and
each of the hooks separately.
We touch those hooks all
throughout the day that we're
compounding, so make sure that
you clean them off all
individually.
Finish cleaning that hang bar.
Pay attention to those brackets.
We'll throw away that wiper, and
we'll hand sanitize with sterile
IPA.
Pick up a fourth clean wiper to
clean the side panel we're
using, overlapping down and up
strokes moving from the interior
of the hood to the outer edge,
and now you can wipe that front
edge.
Throw away that wiper hand,
sanitize with sterile IPA.
You'll pick up our fifth clean
wiper, and we'll clean the
opposite side.
Notice that overlapping down and
up motion moving from the
interior to the exterior.
Throw away that wiper hand.
Sanitize with sterile IPA.
We'll pick up our last wiper.
We'll flip that wiper so that we
have the air flow from the HEPA
filter we're doing side to side,
overlapping strokes moving from
the inside of the PEC till you
reach that outer edge.
We'll hand sanitize and we'll
bring in six new sterile lymph
free towels so that we can start
with our sterile water for
injection.
Hand sanitize your hands with
sterile IPA.
You can separate those wipers.
We'll bring the bottle of the
70% sterile IPA, we'll unscrew
the cap, lightly saturate the
wipers, and then we'll screw on
the cap and we'll bring that
bottle out and we'll hand
sanitize with sterile IPA.
And we're going to begin in the
same order.
We're going to do side to side,
overlapping on the grill of the
HEPA filter.
You're moving from top to
bottom, side to side, until you
get to the bottom.
You'll throw away the wiper,
you'll hand sanitize with
sterile IPA, you'll get a new
wiper, and you'll clean the
ceiling overlapping side to
side, moving from the interior
part of the hood until you get
to the outer edge.
When you finish, you can clean
that outer edge of the ceiling,
get all the hooks and throw the
wiper away.
Hand sanitize with sterile IPA.
Get a new wiper and we will
clean the hang bar and each
individual hook.
We'll finish with the hang bar,
clean the bracket, Throw that
wiper away.
Hand sanitized with sterile IPA.
We'll pick up a new wiper.
We will do overlapping down and
up motion, moving from the
interior part of the hood all
the way to the outer edge.
You can clean that outer edge,
throw the wiper away, hand
sanitize with sterile IPA, get
another clean wiper, do the
opposite side down and up,
strokes overlapping, moving from
the interior to the exterior.
You can clean off that outer
edge.
Throw away your wiper hand,
sanitize with sterile IPA will
flip that last towel over to get
the clean side of that wiper
moving side to side, overlapping
from the inner part of the hood
all the way to the outer edge,
and then you can clean the
outside edge of the hood.
We'll hand sanitize and we'll
want to put the beyond you state
on all of our cleaning supplies.
This is the sterile IPA bottle,
our EPA sterile disinfectant and
our sterile sterile water for
injection bottle.
In this video we will be
cleaning supply items needed to
clean the horizontal laminar
airflow workbench and items
needed to compound the small
volume ampule base preparation.
You will Don non sterile gloves.
It's important that you know how
to move supply items from the
neutral normal pharmacy into the
anteroom, then into the buffer
room.
You will follow your facility's
standard operating procedure.
Our facility uses a germicidal
disposable wipe that is
bactericidal by recidal and
tuberculosis sidal.
You'll wipe all of the supply
bin, the inside and the out, and
you'll get a new wiper each time
you clean a supply item.
And then you'll place it into
this supply bin cleaning the EPA
disinfectant, the 70% sterile
isopropyl alcohol bottle, the
outer packaging, the sterile
water for irrigation.
USP797 also says that you can do
sterile water for injection.
We'll clean the sterile lid free
towel.
We are ready to clean the supply
items for our ampule based
preparation.
We'll get the outer wrapping of
our IV piggyback, and when you
are bringing syringes and
needles and the isopropyl
alcohol prep swabs in, you'll
want to separate all of those
because there's a lot of
particulate when you pull those
apart and you'll clean each of
those items off and put them
into your supply bin.
Notice that the patient CSP
label is in a plastic bag.
You'll want to wipe off that
plastic bag before it comes into
the buffer room.
We do take calculators into the
clean room.
They must be able to withstand
all of the cleaning items.
Use a hard plastic and a hard
plastic for the numbers and
function buttons.
You do want to do all the
calculations before you come
into the buffer room so that you
know that you have all of the
supply items that you need.
The compounder is now prepared
to do the hand hygiene and
garbing procedure.